Welcome everyone welcome to the asher which...deep dive session and
...a program manager in the as your computing I've
...the...for about two years now and I've been working on you know,
the new compute stack that is being introduce under-resourced manager
today so we'll be spending a lot of time talking about itbefore we go to deep I just
...to...get a quick check on how many of, you know, about resource manager of heard about it
and, you know, listen to...about it thirty forty percent so that's good?
Because this is the reason I ask...is a...level session we're going to go deep dive you know,
talk a lot more about the in a compute advancement that we've made so,
it does expect a little bit of understanding of what casual virtual machines is
I hope most of you are new to virtual machines have listen to the introduction to...action
so, this...will be a little bit more high-level so let me just you want...
so hi my name is marshall I'm a program manager on...cloud platform to scene my team
looks after everything related to tooling for what we say hyper
...large-scale compute so as your virtual machines service fabric io
to scenarios everything that goes back right cool.
So, manages slide you give us feedback we'd love to hear feedback from you so we can
...accordingly and...and
...right so ...we covering todaywe're going to focus on.
Heavily on the isv to stack for folks who don't or not
...at build we announced the introduction of the new compute model compute apis
under-resourced manager aviv term this I is vtwo and we're going to color lot
...between today session the second part of...we're going to focus a little bit on how
we are improving the devon test story even further but integration of compute network and
storage stack under-resourced manager...be going deep dive into some of the tempting
...will actually social shows and cool demos...sharepoint and things like that
then will focus a little bit on how to actually deploy complex applications and I
as will pick up a sample will walk through how to build a complex template and
actually go ahead and deployed...the end we'll talk a little bit about the single unify
...for the compute cloud you might have heard some announcements at the keynote or
the foundation session so we'll talk a little bit about that the
...something that you have not seen before right?
Given the fact that there's thirty to forty percent of people who have kind of heard about
...I'm just going to spend a couple of minutes introducing the concepts for
...not heard about it resource groups are up...manager is a new service that is
...and measure has been around for about a year now we've.
We've had support for sql databases websites and a bunch of other
...resource providers but compute network and storage announcement happens today happens with the
build announcement so, I'm going to talk about some basically, you know,
basic...resource group-think of them as a logical container which allows you to
plays a set of resources in a in it together and
resource scope think of an application you...think of an application like say ...you know, like a
...applicant sharepoint, for example, you can choose to...
Different years of those application in espresso in special...for example,
you can say hey I want my...resource group I want mine you know, sequel
...a separate resource group and data...a database theorem differently so you can choose to do that but the
idea behind resource group is that we provide capabilities on the platform which allows you to manage the
entity as a whole a good example would be in a devon test scenario you actually have a single app
...you can choose to delete the entire resource group as a whole which is a big advantage typically if
you think about scenarios what you're doing large-scale applications you have hundred nodes that, you know, spinning up and
spinning down management of those nodes are pretty hard so resource groups allows you the flexibility
to, you know, either delete the entire set of nodes as a single...you make a single
...resource group and we take care of deleting all entities
...now...I want to re-use resource groups...think about it is think...
for properties think about the lifecycle of the resources how do I want my app...look like do I want to
place mightier in a separate entity or do I want...or...in a single resource group it's up to you
can choose but keep in mind the lifecycle aspect of it the second is tagging are
billing think about how you want to tagged resources because what we've enabled is
the capability where you can now getthe tags that are...on resources propagated to the
...any tagged...for example, like say...in application...good...db,
for example, that tag will not just stay in a ui level...for query
will actually propagate through and be available at the end in your customer...at the end of the month
...cs refile so that you can actually go build rich
...charts to say how you know-how much of my each department
cosco building is a key aspect of how you architect your resource...how you place the resources and resource
group another aspect of as it is rule-based
access control think about how who gets access to a particular resources, for example,
if you have a database...you want to actually give access...access only to the database adnan if
you have virtual network instead of networking properties you want to give only the network admin
...access to everybody else can get...access but you want to just
...give write access to the other so think about these different aspects when you are
...creating resource group and placing them in a different entities the last one here is if
you're thinking about high availability or dr scenarios...resource could actually spans
...you actually have among the db which has the primary sitting in let's...best us but the second
...actually second resource sitting in a different region you can choose to actually plays all of that in a single resource
could because the resource...spans an entire...entire globe...as well as regions that
...so keep that in mind ok so the key aspects are if you should,
should resources being a same resource group or not you should always think about the common
lifecycle the patterns the building aspects of it and then
architecture application accordingly and we don't support this for now but we will
act support in the future but even if you make a mistake of actually placing a set of resources
in a specific resource...you're like hey I want to move this to
...entity because that's where the lifecycle matches better...support apis
where you can actually move resources between resource crips in the future to make your management better?
Ok,
the next aspect is you guys have heard a lot about it going to spend a brief amount of time here I'm going to produce
templates template support has existed in the platform for
a about a year now I'm going to go deep into it but I do want to talk about
...of the advantages that it offers when in context of compute
right previously we just had...and databases but with introduction of compute it opens up an entire
gamut of applications that you can now go build an architect
on asher and the inherent capabilities that template language provides a is actually
very helpful because templates themselves are item important just because it's so just by saying the templates
...importantly also means that the apis that are backed by the templates but also
important, for example, if you actually have a virtual machine and...you...with
...of data disks and you actually do a get
...and...back to asher is actually going to accept that request and continue
...process and say it's going to give you a success immediately so all the apis going forward that are supported
...rasio resource manager for compute is item...compute network
...and the...language offers this orchestration capability so,
when I talk about orchestration it has the capability where you can actually define a set of resources to be
dependent on each other say I want to spin up in the case of ad an active directory
...you want to have the primary that...boot-up foursome actually be ready for you want
...your second-rate...can actually express the dependency to say
...to depends on the mone before can actually start up so you actually expressed the dependency at
the infrastructure layer and you know,
with resource groups and resource manager you also get the flexibility of just trashing
...group and you're doing devon...so we don't offer...capability per say but...simplifies
your rollback mechanism...you just start...the deployment you push something to resource group and...hey,
you know, like step three of the whole deployment just failed instead of
just trying to fix that and go and...around with...you can just say
...scratch is actually pretty easy to do that management and as I said earlier with the
integration of compute network and storage it coupling itself with the...cash
...sequel databases of website it opens and entire gamut of applications for you now you can orchestrate
...build an application or a template which contains all of the as
...manager with compute offering so it gives you a lot more flexibility you know,
review template files us source files that are checked in manage to maintain and,
you know, used by you guys and...stored on your
site and it is continuously used for deployment purposes into measure and,
the parameterization...capability in the temperate itself makes it repeatable so
if you actually have, you know, let's say a sharepoint...you're doing some devon
...if you actually go architect one template you can reuse the
...again and again for rebuilding your app again,
so, it's it becomes a very repeatable very easy with...previous cases you have to go
write your owns shell scripts our in lc...or partial scripts to go build your app on as
you're using compute ...simplifies that drastically so devon...becomes fundamentally...
Okay, so, just kind of touch on some of the you know,
the big improvements here complexities made simple I'll show you some samples about the complex applications that
have gone ahead and build on measure now you can blend and build applications using
...and different paths services that are available in the platform when I talk about passive as a
sequel or websites I'll
dived deep into some of the scaleability aspects of the you virtual machines and...the improvements
...major...now you'd be able to spin up you know, hundreds of...really
...it really parallel and the integration of rule-based access control...tags you know,
offers a great flexibility for enterprise and devon test scenarios which will diving
and what you're seeing that on the right side right-hand side is a new a community template section that
...launched with actual this is going to contain about sixty to seventy...templates which are you know,
some of them are basic starter templates that lets you get started we also have a lot
of complex application templates and will be going little-bitty into that...session?
Okay, so, what are the biggest advantages that are being offered and, it comes to
...computes that first one really is the...parallel deployment of virtual machines one of the common
...coins that used exist with xml based apis that support
supported in the platform was we were not able to process of the address
...would not process simultaneous deployment of virtual machines which you would have faced was obviously and,
that's a massive improvement...the stack now you can actually go ask for let's say
twenty m in availability said if you want and we'll go process all of those twenty
...in parallel so,
that's a big difference than what we got used to perform the second aspect of it is
the platform offered the concept of availability sets that we actually physically
please your virtual machines when you say to...and availability sept we physically placed...and to separate
...some to for domains as we call it this ensure that you had high availability from the platform
...platform roles...now with the introduction of the new compute apis we are increasing that
...three-four domain so for...that require you know,
like core...workloads now you can actually get...ensure that the platform will not take the third you
...will only take one...down in the tvs at any given time
...this ensures that you always have...to make sure you don't obviously you don't go down and there's
a physical of flac failure and, we've made a lots of lots of improvements around the
...extension capabilities as well to make it work well with the templates and...be...
a detail on that ...made a lot of changes around ...and how things are done you don't have to
use a certificate anymore you just...can directly...a...to rsa format
for the certificates going forward and ...support was announced
on the xml based apis two weeks ago with this announcement we also are introducing
the premium storage support on top of the...some based apis aren't...resource manager?
Okay.
Now I want to spend a little bit of time talking about the...extensions how many of, you know,
about aggravate extensions?
...k so I have to spend more time okay so, actually
...are so,
...I is virtual machines what you get is the capability of getting just infrastructure getting the...cloud but,
that's not all of it right there's just...of work lot-of in the in configuration that you need to do to actually
go get your app up and running inside the virtual machine so we've partnered but a lot of you know,
a third-party vendors and who've actually, you know, and,
we have some folks from doctor sitting right in front we have a...extension also on the platform we
...partnered with a lot of the third-party vendors to actually go get the extensions like
chef and pop it into the platform to make it easy for customers to in the and configuration on
...in addition to third-party tools like chef and
pop it and darker we've also focused on getting the basic scripting capability so we
...have customs crypt windows we have customs script linux extensions we can actually write a...script a
python script and ask for to be run inside the which machine...a very easy fashion ...and linux and,
we also have first-class dc support the desired state
configure support from partial we also have first-class support for that and...model so the
...works is that the extensions are created first party you know,
...agents if you will that are being...the platform and v replicate them all over the what's the
number of virtual machines creator measure we and you say hey I want
push of dc agent into the platform we actually take that agent from one of
...globally replicated stores and push that agent inside the box...platform
...constant communication with that agent to be able to give instructions in one case you can say hey
...on the script right we actually take description actually
send instructions down to the agent to be able to go to that work so it actually happens inside the
vm and the our of this with...resource manager really is now
where you can express dependencies between these
crypt files as well so you can actually say I have to be m I want to...between them but you can
express a dependency their scripts to on vm to can take a...crypt one-on-one so
you have in...configuration dependency that you can not just express on the infrastructure layer but now
you're expressing dependencies between descriptive positive running across the different...now in
...configuration of...just becomes a really simple so now you can express
dependencies not just the infrastructure layer now you're expressing dependency surprise across the
application layer between the different alignments and you are building complex applications on measure.
Another key part above the new compute network and storage stack
or the changes that we've done is also gone ahead and fundamentally looked at how do we want to
expose networking to customers how do you want...bare-bones networking constructs
...so the first thing that we've done is that earlier used to have the virtual machines would
carry the networking configuration like, you know, I want to reserved ip or I want I want to endpoint for the
...all of the networking...part of the virtual machine itself...broken apart we've really taken the
lego blocks of networking and just started provisioning them so,
going forward you'll have a network interfaces a first-class object to be able to attached to
...so that's the first thing that you create and important part about the network interface here is that
it's not it is a floating network interface when you actually delete vm it's actually not going to get
deleted so the lifecycle of the networking configuration is actually separate from the virtual machine itself and
the good part about this is when you do complex application configuration like, you know,
I want use security group a and then put it in virtual network
be all of the configuration just stays with the version of with the network interface and including
...so you can actually float the network interfaces around to the different virtual machines that you need and, load balance
or this is one of the things that you used to offer as an implicit capability in the old model
load balance is now first-class resource that allows you to define load balance of internal
or public and then attach the net...to the load balance and say hey
...the next I want to load balance as part of this load balance of so you get the flexibility of doing that and,
another improvement that we've made is that on the virtual networking apis if you think about the existing
models used to have a...based model...it was xml to them and if
you had let's say ten virtual networks and subscription you had to toggle and operate using that single
...xml...and actually thaler all...network into the virtual networks in the stack with
improvements here now you get the flexibility of dealing with an operating only for a single virtual network
and we've also added support for targeting individual virtual network through partial and, prospects
...like...let's commands as well so which is it's very flexible and,
we've also added support for public ip addresses we had support for this on the old stack as well but,
...also added in the vtwo stack public ip...can be dynamic or static it can be assigned either to a
...or to load balance and.
The last one here is the network security groups are network security groups
offers both inbound and outbound rules we can actually goal filter based on a
...the inbound rules that I want to set...public ip address or you can actually confident
...as well ok so what are the notable changes in the
apis...things that we havefundamentally changed we used to have something called
...cloud service which offer a lot of these capabilities that's been modified to us
...blocks really so the cloud...that it offered will used to offer us a public ip address
of that used to give and implicit load balance or it used to give...implicit concept called
and availability set the networking configurations...to the virtual machines all of those
...was so tightly coupled with...virtual machine and the object itself we've really broken
them part given the lego blocks if you will and actually
ask you guys to construct and actually make them stitch together the way that you things that I
critical about it and we...lot of samples to make it easy for you to understand how this can be done
and the samples include not just add the template level but also includes you know,
goes from templates to
...partial command let's two-c allies support including client libraries we've had
...added support...samples for all of these different these so you can actually go to that.
Another key part that I do want to mention here is that going forward in the
...stack virtual machines need to be created...in a virtual network
...you cannot create a virtual machine just by itself it has to be placed in...network is
a security by default we...make sure that every virtual network...creator measure
...a virtual network and you have to explicitly choose to say that you want to
place...internet...creative em by itself it's not going to get and public
...like before it gets secure by default.
And, in you have to ask for public ip address and then you can float these ip addresses that you
...so this is a big difference and what we're doing here?
And, no, more implicit dns names you know, used to get something like something that lot-of
...net if you don't want...you're like hey I don't care about it was just, you know,
added we don't provide that anymore if you want to dns name for your app you need to ask...unique
...public ip address so if...have gone back to the basics of just saying how do we introduce networking how
do we do networking as the basic building blocks and that's what we've solved the new apis.
Okay,
so, with that I'm going to hand-off to boris and talk a little bit about how we've simplify devon test
...so how many of you use adrg iso devon test?
How many of you have actually?
Donner sharepoint deployment before
...okay the reason why I bring that up like in
a microsoft world one of the complexes...deployments or topology as well as
...upon on from and ...what we're going to show what I'm going to show you today
how simple it is so why do we think like the new virtual machine stagg
...new measure stack has drastically simplified as your use iterative
...so first of all when you build your or...days so
I like to call it when you spun of your environment's and measure you probably road tons of partial
scripts because you want to have an automated and repeatable workflow the problem
of our shells scripts at least my experience of what we heard from customers is even though you
...if you want to another environment
that's exactly like that the one that you spun up you run into issues more
...on you need to debugged you need to figure out what's not working and things like that so
it's really cumbersome to share like those our shells scripts of a configuration so
...as a resource manager because we have a declarative way of describing an
environment it's really nice and easy to repeat
...deployments over and over again
another important aspect and that's another big difference my hash mentioned that as a
resource managers item potent that means like think about a partial scripts that you have to
...you want to create a resource and you want to created...to check if the resource...and things like that
...it was all an effort to put that
code in there to check if the resource there and you need to catch it and you need
...handle that situation so...resource manager being item
coda and it's already build so you can think about you have a template to defines
...you publish it or you deployed
once you environment is there now
you're going to repeat this deployment and you just make one change let's say you add another server to it as
a resource manageable only...that additional server to it so that the
sub the succeeding deployments are really fast because
...changes are being impacted by the next employment that's really great?
So, another another advantage of having everything
...one template is you basically can manage entire
application as an entity before you had like I remember when I will like our transcripts
...partial environment tons of scripture tama descriptive things like that
...really hard to keep track of here with the template approach...have
everything in one template and you can...you can source control it you can even track like once
source controlled who may changes so you can really ensure that
everything the entire application is managed as an entity the other aspect I mean I work on the
visual studio side for us the way we think about it is configures code
soulful obviously like a template because it's just a
...file it can be easily integrated in are alike lifecycle tooling
like continue is build and delivery pipeline release manager and the
deaf test left that we have announce...so once you define your environment as a
...blocks easily into our into our stack and if you don't use our stack
it's also good because you can just use cdl high-power shell or any scripting language
...deployed a template another advantage is really easy monitoring
...because with...we...you get exactly actually you get a little
bit more capabilities when it comes to monitoring and alerting so as my hash
described there is this notion of extensions and there is a it's
called actual diagnostics extension which is basically an
...that runs on ibm's collects data about the machine...
that run on top of it so you get that for free its easily to integrated and your application
or you environment is being monitored and obviously you can also hook it into
our alerting system.
Another example
...or wide assist drastically simplified how many of you run a
...test environment...to connected back to on from,
for example, to get certain data so...that we also like make sure you have a good
hybrid connectivity...thing you can use appoint...connection side-to-side or express
...so it's really easy now with that because we talked a lot let's do the first
...and back to here.
Okay, everybody...okay.
All right so what I have here is virtual studio but...not
...studio code project whatsoever it's really
just a template here it's called deployment template
...jason and you can think about this template describes a
very complex sharepoint form it has like a sharepoint front-end it has a
...and app server and it has a database layer so think about
it could be any topology like that very sophisticated
topology of course I want to follower golden rules I don't want
to start everything from scratch because if I needed to build...template from scratch would take me forever and
it was probably like really hard to do so,
my hash pointed out we have the get hub or them as a marketplace with all those templates
...can go-there grab a template...needs use it put it in visual studio and
customizing or someone in your company might already have defined
...environment in a chase and template and you just elise to the sourceto the to ripple
open it and you can start customizing so as I mentioned what I have here is
...template and I don't want to dive into the tooling here
but the nice thing about it is because it's
a very complex template is we have a so-called chase
an outline view so we don't want to build a designer anything like that we just want to give you an idea
hey what resources what parameterization being used by
...template and make it really easy for you to customizing so in here if
I look at the resources I see I got quite a bunch here is like all my
variables and my virtual machines and things like that and if I
wanted to add something to a resource I could do that but just clicking
at the resource and then I could bring up.
The add new...dialogue
...basically what it what it holds is a bunch of chase and snippets.
And,...so
...a bunch of chasing snippets that define artifacts in your environment so, for example,
you could add another virtual machine
...or another extension or another network
so as I mentioned before ready deployed the template to
...just to prove it it's here it's basically sharepoint pharma
measure deployed through visual studio so what I'm going to do now is ...here look at
...template the snippet editor okay what I want to do now is I want to show you
the item potency and what I've done here is I created a very simple
low test that basically hammers the sharepoint
website and because I haven't changed anything on my front-end I'm going to start deploying
a template and you should see when we're in a portal that it's still excepting requests?
Students let's run the test.
...test is actually using...virtual studio testing service it's also cloud-based
are not executing...locally because my machine wouldn't be what doesn't have to...to hold
organizations right it's very easy to integrate only downside is it now needs to
requires...resources will take all...should be fairly?
While we.
Configuring the
agents why we start that I'm going to go and deploy.
Via template.
So, in here this is the deploy to
resource group so there is no and again there is no
...studio matching because what we used to deployed a template is really
powerful it's a...that you can just use take
customize so it's what every id pro uses so there is no magic
in visual studio whatsoever so in here I'm going to choose my subscription
already have my resource group and then I just want to enter when I show you to paris meters because you
see on the left-hand side in the chase and outline view I had quite a bunch of
our meters but this is fairly, fairly convenient because it gives it
a paradigm and you just need to add what you want what you want named resources
spain so...and then kick-off...it?
Little...so now
...started and if we look down here.
If everything goes well we hope.
It basically has a template is valid so it's been validated by
measure resource manager everything is good in a template then it starts creating
a template deployment and then you should see any minute that the resource creation
is fairly quick
unique to think about is like virtual machines virtual networks and everything but this is
really item potency it really goes in there and says okay already have that I haven't touched
...has changed and basically just goes to the next step it starts
answers availability...storage cones.
Succeeded so,
let's do one thing here as you can see like now it's really start
going right hey I already have to research resource hasn't change go to the next one go
to the next one and while it's doing that if we go in here that's
the server explorer I can go to the sharepoint front-end
click on configure which takes me to portal deep links into the portal we don't want
to have any configuration staff and...studio because we really think
...portal or powerless right we to do that so we're going to take into poorly here.
And, then you can see
or sharepoint virtual machine is still running while...deployment is
...and that's I think is really great especially for deft has scenarios.
All right on with that I'm going to switch back to
slide's but I think because most of you have already heard or seen about.
Resent about tags.
And, my hash already mention it I just want to point out a
...things because the tagging.
You think about tagging it's
name value pairs that you can assign to resources are resource groups so not
...test scenario that's pretty convenient because as my hash mentioned you can actually tag
...and say this is my definite...that's my test environment but
they're all the scenarios that I want to point out because there
is like you get a pretty decent inside in your costing right because you can also
tag by department you could say hey those resources are
being used by the finance department those resources are being used by
the engineering department and then you're building...to filter out...tax and you haven't manual of
...the reason why mentioning that is because we also got a lot of complains about our billing system and it was hard to
figure out who uses what resources...
saying what the tagging is good for you could actually tag...jones who works in the as
...resource manager very good example I just repeat that you could actually tag
...resource worth responsible person for the resource for think about you have a
measure mission critical application something goes wrong and you could actually just go to the
...and say who should not contact here so those are just couple high-level samples
...is great the next thing just one of briefly touch on is
research spaced access control so I'm doing a lot of ev season
redman up there about...test in a measure and the very first question we get
okay how do I handle
...subscription management because how should I do this with
developers with my departments so on so forth so far you could only do it like
on a subscription level and you had to add like other people in your department
to subscription or each...its own subscription so with our bag
you really have of at granularity permission control of
...resources so you can basically say I want to give think
about multi-layered application I only want to give a certain?
Group of people access to my
...I just want to give a certain set of people access
to my web front-ends servers and it goes even that...you could say I want to give
the access to...I want to give them permission to certain actions so,
for example, I could say okay I'm going to trust my hash to
access my machine so he can remote desktop into it but
I won't let him shut it down because I needed for demo so this is coming I think
So, overall I think our...way of controlling access
to your resources and we got that feedback from you over and over again and there
...so thing it's really good I just want to skip over those two slides here because.
Going to switch back to them.
Right cool so I think that was a good introduction about how we can continue use you know,
devon tester measure... using templates...new apis.
What I'm going to focus a little bit on is the of data...a great story when,
you know, the announcement of apis and template support now you have to models in which you can actually go
...virtual...can actually say hey I'm going to define it using a template...app
...apply that or you can use the old model the way you guys have done before
to say I'm going to optimize own custom partial script is going to create using you actually in,
for example, so, we will continue to support both models
...support for template is really all about the ability where it makes it
easy for you to deploy an application now when you think so
we talked a lot about first-time deployment now when you think about a greater update story you have
the flexibility do whatever you want you can choose to say my deployment model and
...management model that as you're going for is going to be all about templates because the templates...item...
and all that you can do is you can actually go deploying app and say two months later you come back and say hey my perform of
...and performance is not that great...I'm actually going to add a cashier and you want to bring a cashier with a
couple more beams, for example, you just take the same template file...modify the temperate file to say
had couple more ibm's just deployed again so your update
...a great story can still be used...dom using the same...
orange completely say hey I'm just going to use this for my first-time deployments and then use this out,
you know, template but after the first-time deployments done online maintenance and management and for...updates like
...added data...I want to change that gets all of that can done be done using existing
tools introduce...and continue to use the...like tools and that's
...absolutely update you so we all that we've opened up...another layer are model that
makes it simply the job simplified...end of the day you get the tools that you that used
to exist before continue to manager which...the same way like you did
before okay now the manageability in the debugging story
is now is interesting as well because now you're triggering a template deployment it's going to run for like let's say,
you know,
half an hour one-hour right so...aspects of is actually very critical because let's say you
...fifty-minute and durant app is dead so
it's not very useful so we have added support at multiple levels we have
supported the partial tooling we have...exploits the likely we have support in the portal for
you to be exactly see what happened to a template deployment let's say you had ten resources that
your spinning up you can actually go exactly look at van was the seventh resource that was fun up
what was the error message you can actually have a fridge filter
...shows you what happened we also support auditing like any other...you know, like we...
of before auditing on the all of these operations so we store the data...nineties you can actually look at what
happened during this time and another key part here that I do want to touch on is when
you use resource groups and actually have a bunch of resources in some cases you have
hb data like storage...a lot of...very helpful?
Maximal deletion of resource could means that accident
pollution of data so we support the capability of management...so you can actually go into resource
...locks and resources that doesn't have to believe that you can actually protect those resources from
be deleted so when you actually try to read delete
resource group all the other resource will go away but the ones that you had the management locks on will not be
...we stuck patrol...looking at the large you'll be able to figure out saying I've
...management lock on resource to ensure it doesn't get accidentally deleted so it
is powerful of the same time you can make mistakes we provided the capabilities...you can...use the management...skip.
And, we've also added support for resources...as a dot com today in the session I'm not going to go
dive deep into it but do note that link the tree structure view
all the entire subscription can actually go look at the just the data like it would
just execute the get calls and all the resources and list to the tree structure view it's
a very helpful very powerful tool especially if you're using the and extensions you can
...authoring or developing scripts yang quickly look at what happened to might the output of my skip
you don't have to go to partially don't have to go to see like you just run a template to quickly go
...resources rasio dot com look at the vm and see what went wrong on the popular script executions...very powerful?
Okay, so, let me switch here.
To a quick demo.
...able to see okay the front okay.
Right so what I have here is which is to your code so, what I'm doing here is I'm going to
have a deployment which is think of it is a scalable vector of I have a set of the m I've
...as the front-end now I'm going to showcase an example that is how we
have simplified the ability that you can now scale that web...in a very simple fashion so in
the sample we're looking at a template which has the pedometer section so you know, the
...templates of contains for important sections forces the parameters,
parameters make a template repeatable more...more you parameterized more options you have or the flexibility that you
...to repeatedly deploy that again and again the second section is the
variable section mostly runtime constance that you can assign the third section is really the resources
section resources are the set of resources that...spinning up for app classrooms outputs,
outputs are used for looking at whether...operational successful or not so in this case you know,
I'm obviously, you know,...using password as...input storage account...input and
...but the important part that I'd want you...note here is accepting of value call number of instances
in this template the number of instances here I just said hey I want to go...up ibm's so
that's important now after that instances a...resources action that I'm spinning up I'm speaking
of a storage account by my disks will be placed and creating virtual network there my...m will
replaced now let's look at the public ip addresses so in this section...want you guys
to focus on this aspect so what we have here is a new capability
...copy capability inside the template language so what does offers is the capability
where you can
...this in a template file and actually asking to be executed and number of times so in the case
...excepted that's...what this is going to do is actually going to create to public ip addresses
simon simultaneously because there are no dependencies and I can also use the capability called copy
index which allows me to name the resources correctly so in this case what happens is the resource
...be named...zero public ip one
...and start creating that resource the good part is I can now extend the copy
index capability to other resources as well so actually have the same thing here
for network interface I'm saying here's the...and creating to network interfaces because I want
...to virtual machines so you can continue to extrapolate that and then it keeps
applying itself now another important part here is that I can also express dependencies between a
number of resources and creating so I created to public ip
addresses and to mix I can also expressive dependency that says?
My...zero actually depends on public ip zero so
implicitly without actually having to go ahead and declare all of these instances again and again you have the
capability to just, you know, implicitly specify here's...dependency so public near-zero
...depends on public ip...being available...one depends on public ip one being available to express that
dependency right here and the same applies for virtual machines I go and extend that...use that you've
...all over now what I have here is that I've already gone ahead and deployed this template with a couple of...
so I'm just going to go...quickly show that so if you see this I actually have a couple of the m here.
Medium zero...one with a couple of...ip is.
Can also look at the scalable that...here and there a couple of instances of virtual machines
...what I'm going to do is I'm going to quickly modify?
I have a parameters file for this template...quickly modify this to say twenty so the
simple click of changing this number I'm going-to go ahead and now start to deploy this.
Whole thing so I'm doing a new actually subscript deployment into the scalable that
...resource group I'm...that I'm giving the...of the parameter file that I just modified and the
...to the template file the template file with the same template...used before.
Disco make sure...
Okay, all right.
All right so these templates are posted on to addresses manager the template is valid...deployment is now
being created in this case what happens is it now it's going to look at wait we mone and mtwo
...up and running and the...asking for twenty more...so will automatically start provisioning
the meaning eighteen the end...based on this template so it shows the item potency nature of
a template it also shows the scalable nature of the stack so as you can see slowly the ip addresses
will start getting created the network interfaces that are...on...start getting created.
And, this is a key part not just purely from a deployment standpoint but also the fact
that the scalability of the stack right previously if you wanted to go do this against
...based apis you would have to wait a couple of minutes for equal to the next operation would not be able to add the
gm's but improvement here really is around how we
have fundamentally simplified the ability to go to this forced at the language
level and template you can just do this by single change a number and also the underlying
...significantly improved to provide...capability for scaling up really fast.
Okay.
You can see these...are going to continue to run
...ensure in shortness of time I'm going to jump back in again to the slide deck.
So, the next part over going to focus onhow do we go about...complex applications now we just
looked at a simple app that just, you know, the front...I had a website running there I just...it
...not that big a deal sure we know we could do this using partial script but we simplify this using
...manager but how do we fundamentally simplify complex right so one of the things
that, you know, we've heard about you must have heard about it before but, you know,
we have support for a lot of the windows and linux workloads on the platform but,
the key part and we have, you know, the tooling support
...in configurations for but the important part here is now the work that you've done
for application templates if you look at the bottom most part of it those are all the different apps
...have templates for already longer dp or...containers and actually code deploying and app the
...or...data stacks so we have real-world production application
templates that are available right now for us to go on trial right previously if you had to go
to this by yourself and if you want to architect this application it would take
...take any like couple of weeks to just know what you need to do understand
...different constructs but now what we've done is we've simplified the ability that these
applications templates are available for you to go start from...actually just start from a
...cluster...go look at all here's always been a
...cassandra cluster you take that template back go...in a city modifications...
that you want and then go deployed again so you get that flexibility from the platform and?
The next part is.
When you think about ...templates on this section what I'm going to do is I'm going to give you guys a little bit more insight into
what you need to think about when deploying...templates for your complex applications just
...faults think of them and break them down into infrastructure...vm configuration pieces and,
you break them down into infrastructure think of them as a what I'm an
...the template for...just for a single production environment or I might architect...this for multiple and one
...notion of doing this for like a deft devon
...testament a product...what my different requirements how many of
...do I need to...and each one of these different...if I were to use the same template again and again and,
then for common application infrastructure...I'm going to show you a sample
it would be a good idea to break them apart like...creating a single virtual network where the entire thing is going to be
deployed I would recommend that you actually create a separate template just for the infrastructure pieces like
creating a storage count operating the virtual network and leave the other pieces out
and the other part is you can also leave...and configuration the separate template you can actually go
...template that just is responsible for deploying the app and configuring the app let's among the
db or other apps right so you can keep separate template and obviously the multiple
actually resources like, for example, if you're doing websites or...db keeping...gone ahead and deploy
...created five or seven different templates now how do you go
...them together so we have the capability in the platform template linking and I'll show you sample
of that is actually going to go ahead and allow you to stitch all of these different template
and express dependencies between them you can express dependencies between the not just
...particles express dependencies between in the and aspects of it when you think about the
indian configuration what I need to do inside the vm always think about
architected in a way you take out and...apart the common
...that you need to run across a bunch of nodes and actually have separate scripts for that and then do the app specific
...as well so if I were to just think about this and look at,
you know, try...diagram around it what you will have is you will have
...you have to define the set of parameters that you want to plays or accept your template across different
environments...test and...and then have a master template is responsible for actually going
and deploying the whole app but knows how to call into the rights of apps
...the dependencies I'll show you some samples that and have some
logic or strategies for how you would place or except input from the use of that targets
different alignments dev test...production and then have these different member resource templates
of shared resource templates when I say member resource these are templates that would be responsible for the
blind the actual the m and stuff like that but...resource template more are on the infrastructure and storage
counts and things that you need to go create and, in other cases the...could also be a website and,
then the actual you can actually have a simple template that is responsible for spinning of singly
...and you can go ahead and use the looping capability to call it again and again you can accept the user
input says...up seventy m...cassandra cluster but actually have a single
bm setup clustered and then call it again and again sometimes to actually go...can architect doesn't...app from a single template
...and then from the template file you can choose to...into the different extensions
or the scripts themselves and say hey, you know, go called one of these basic script that are just pushed pull down
...the muggy or the cassandra database specific, you know, you know,
exes...files and then run specific
...to do configuration based on...that your...and for example,
for the data in some cases the shatters templates could also choose...call-in to you know,
the scripts themselves so in...in this example what I'm going to do is I'm going to talk a little bit about
...app which we've built and it's available for us to go try is the data stacks
on which machines we do so, datasets as an industry leader in developing and you
know, delivering solutions based on apache cassandra right...it's and they have
two skews available they actually have a communities to available they also have a datasets enterprise skew available for
...to guys to go use and...commercial advisory
no sequel database right so, a we have we have quite a few customers of already started using cassandra on as
...so what we're going to look at is how do we go spin up this and our cluster and measure is
going to look at how you can have this front-end or the...vm and then you can specify
accept a set of input nodes are input vm from the customer and be able to spin up the entire data
text cassandra cluster okay here's a quick view of what you know,
when I walk through the template...when I go to the following...a bunch of these things I just want to give you a perspective and we
talked about the must attempted that's the as a deployed a json ...we talked about you know,
breaking apart the different pieces you could think of the
data that the cassandra nodes themselves that could be the ephemeral
...you actually have a file the defines that specific configuration you have the...center vm with which
you actually login monitor the entire datasets...that could be separate you know,
json file I've all the also broken down the installation of the...configuration the
ops intervene as a separate json...the extension from the script running inside the vm to configure
...center is...faulty and actually break all of these different files and scripts themselves to go
...run so let me go ahead and switch over?
So,...earlier demo that I showed succeeded
...important part...here is that if you actually see we started
one eleven but one fifteen four minutes you
get twenty virtual machine which is phenomenal different right so.
All right let me jump back.
Let me go here okay so.
If you look at here's the ...pfizer folders that...that actually construct this data stacks
of template so as I mentioned earlier we have a attribute deployed
...some that's your master file and then you have the if
...nodes which is the specific nodes that are the json files that are used for spinning up the data
...the nodes and you actually have the...center resources start json which is actually
...center configuration of the vm...the obstinate of
...install resources of just running the customs crypt extension inside the which machine to configure
...center so if you look at this template once again very similar you have the parameter section and
...important part here with this template specifically is that accepts.
Cluster node count this is the number of nodes that you want to specify the
cassandra clusters it's very similar to the other template...used but here will be using a different strategy for actually going
and applying such a complicated app so let's go back in here.
First thing that I want to point out to you guys here is the resources section we have a model
...I talked about how you can actually have different templates we have introduces model that you
can have a template linking capability this...specifically here.
This template linking capabilities what allows you to teach all of these different templates together to global
...I to of app right so, we...passing the location of a template
link here and say hey here's the location for this particular deployment which is the first one here is the
share template url which means that it's been of the virtual...accounts actually setting of the environment
...the basic infrastructure...starting from there so that's the first template first deployments being
skewered the second deployment here is the cluster nodes you're actually triggering the deployment of the cluster
...specifically your creating let's say we start with the datasets cassandra cluster five nodes are seven nodes those
are the nodes that will get created next so it's the cluster nodes template url and that gets created
if you look at it actually...the note camp information...gets passed into five or seven or ten
except that input and actually goes...create so many other nodes if
you look inside that template that is actually going to create one virtual machine with a copy having seminar
fighting...input.
And, the last section is the ...center thing let me go back here.
So, this is the actual quick...templates action that I talked about earlier so these this is the announcement
...made if you actually go to...dot com go-to community and then go to the
template section you actually land here these are the different templates that I talked about earlier so we have
about sixty or seventy...templates and very,
you know, application oriented templates as...we have caf...parkharden works cloud
error data stacks all these different available on the platform let's go pick data stacks and...to.
So, right from agile dot com you can actually go ahead and deploy this template into your subscriptions we can actually
...see deployed...
What this is going to do is it actually goes going-to-take the...on file and it's going to take it into the
porta dot com parse the file and allow you to
...the parameters and actually go to apply this right into your subscription so that's what you're saying so
now it is loading the whole template into the portal and
it's going to generate a custom ui for you actually go and take the based on a number
...we looked at like let's say all of these different parameters that we're looking at
here will now be loaded up here in this template file will actually allow you to...this file in a single click?
Yep, so, that template file is now directly loaded into the portal from a single click you have
...you have the flexibility to go.
Into the values for this...is the entire template file that we just looked
at it actually has all the deployments I'm going to just go ahead and save it...edit the parameters.
Is tanks...six-seven?
School use that theme.
Go ahead and get some parameters.
Ethree.
...up five of cluster.
Perfect...existing subscription...create a...
Research group.
And,...pick.
Secure postings...
And, this is...so deploying data stacks and measure which used to be...a long
processes fundamentally simplified...where you can just go from any of the existing templates you can
just go start creating that deployment just not possible before so that's what we've done so,
let's give it a minute I'll go back to show you the progress of the deployment but given
interest of time I already have a data stacks such template that I was that
I've already deployed so I'm going to just so many little bit the same
five instance deployment I had created you can actually see...virtual machines here that's five data
...notes and one of center node and I'm going to just want
...to the here's the ops...write the network interface for the...if you look closely
here's the public ip this for that vm and I'm going to navigate to show you the exact.
Dns name so this is the...that we're going to...and look at the data stacks configuration.
So, this right here is that location so it's data stacks.
Which is six...about...com...with the single click what-you got was a five node data stacks
cassandra cluster in just less than fifteen minutes which was not possible before so that's the our of
the a single note the
...manager integrated compute you can look at the nodes...actually look at what's happening
in each one of those different nodes what's the running tasks all of this is possible which just a single click?
Cool so,
just kind of wrapping up the last part about this is all of these templates
in the language that we talked about the apis themselves not just one template side but also the apis
...tools and...partial commandments all of this is going to be consistent
...I...consistent this is a single unify
asher api stack that is going to be shipping with on...as well so the amount of
the effort the code the anything that you any absentee build
are right on top of the apis for the vtwo
...is we to stack is going to be consistent so the same aps will actually work against a measure on
...as well and I'm going to give it back to...so you can actually do a quick demo.
So, what do you guys things so far like...stove?
All right sake of time as my hash mentioned by being consistent we truly
means what you've seen here you will be able to do exactly
the same thing on premises and jan on premises environment over
time just to prove the point here that we are not just making that up I can
show you work-in-progress right now switching back to.
So, again, this visual studio I know it's hard and I assertions to look at
virtual studio but it gets the point across thing so if I want to
start with a new template...I could do that here hopefully.
Click as a resource group and now you can think about you get this template selection
...as I mentioned will integrate with get hop so you will be able to
...down from get hub or from any other repository so let's check the
virtual machine template for now just a very simple on and what you'll get
is basically project I will show you before with...sharepoint template but the biggest difference and
again that's work-in-progress the biggest difference now is that?
If I'm going to go in here so here's my temperatures to set.
This template now if I common here and say deploy create
a new deployment so it's he's my account...sign-in with might be
shown account but it also knows I have a on
premise measure environment so I can come in here and say hey which
...want to...that thing too you want to deployed into public...you want to deployed into the private
...so here I'm going to choose private cloud.
And, then...my subscription it knows it's actually pretty cool I think because I'm
...with my idea...knows that I have access to private cloud lists dn
...access to
...resource groups and again there's no resource corbin there right now but I think you get
to point so eventually at some point you will be able
to take that very same template and just decide which environment you want
to employed into and I think this is a really,
really great story we have here and was that was really a very short demo
...we just want to prove the point that we're working on that so.
All right so in closing I think we wanted to get you guys...on the new
...we to stack some of the...made not just the fact that it kiss come under
as resource manager but also that...been fundamentally improvements and features that
...been added we've gone back talk the talk a little more about the networking constructs
...into the fundamentals broken down...lego blocks and
aviv added phenomena more capabilities on the and extensions and how it integrates with reese's manager
...actually go build and app think of apps more than the infrastructure that was the
goal...so much...moi?